Francheska Guzmán Flores

Software Test Engineer

Carolina, PR | Tel. +1 (787) 410-9414 | https://francheska.dev



About

Francheska has 8+ years of combined experience in manual and automated software testing, quality assurance, and web development. ISTQB Certified Tester with strong analytical skills, problem solver, detail-oriented, and interpersonal abilities.

Skills

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, C#, Selenium, Cypress, Mocha, Cucumber, Gherkin Language, WordPress, React.js, Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Azure Test Plans, Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite (PowerMapper), Wave, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft SQL Server, Postman.

Languages: Spanish (native), English (intermediate).

Work Experience

Abarca Health LLC - Pharmacy Benefit Manager (PBM)

San Juan, PR

Apr 2022 - Present

- Software Test Engineer II
- Collaborate with Agile Team members.
- Participate in the Scrum Sprint ceremonies.
- Develop test cases in Azure Test Plans based on business requirements and both functional and non-functional specifications.
- Execute test cases and document the results.
- Write detailed bug reports.
- Query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.
- Perform regression testing, API testing using Postman, and exploratory testing sessions.
- Review pull requests.
- Acquire knowledge of the Healthcare, Pharmacy, and Pharmacy Benefit Management industries, as well as Medicare and CMS regulations.

INVID LLC - Information Technology Company

San Juan, PR

Software QA Tester II

Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

- Contributed to the creation of quidelines to improve internal QA/QC procedures.
- Provided training about manual testing activities.
- Created and locally ran automated UI test scripts using Cypress, Cucumber, and Mocha.
- All duties and responsibilities mentioned in the previous role (Software QA Tester I).

Software QA Tester I Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

- Performed static testing in requirements and design (mockups).
- Created test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Ran manual tests and performed exploratory testing in web and mobile applications.
- Conducted usability/accessibility testing for WCAG 2.1, ADA, and Section 508 compliance by using tools such as the Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, and Wave.
- Reported and tracked issues identified during testing activities to ensure defect resolution and testing completion.
- Collaborated in the development of new ideas to resolve system issues and improve current systems.
- Basic query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.

New York Film Academy - School of Film and Acting

New York, NY

Front End Web Developer

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

- · Coded e-mail marketing campaigns and landing pages based on mockups and provided content.
- Segmented mailing lists by making queries on the database.

- Delivered approved e-mail campaigns to the target market using both Campaigner and iContact e-mail marketing automation platforms.
- Made updates to the New York Film Academy websites and WordPress sites.
- Coded the new version of the online applications.
- Debugged e-mail campaigns, landing pages, online applications, and websites.

Second Language Design - Creative and Marketing Agency Web Developer

New York, NY Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

- Developed WordPress sites for clients based on mockups and provided content.
- Performed QA testing across modern platforms and devices.
- Added meta tags for SEO and set up Google Analytics.

uTest - Crowdsourced Software Testing Community Software Tester

Remote

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

- Executed test cases in web and native applications.
- Performed exploratory testing sessions.
- Submitted detailed bug reports.

Projects

Weather Forecast

https://francheska-guzman.github.io/weather-forecast

Weather Forecast is a web app that provides information such as temperature, pressure, and humidity of five cities. Developed with React.js and requesting the data from a third party API.

Education

CodeBridge - Web Development Immersive Program

New York, NY

Certificate of Completion

2017

Per Scholas and General Assembly

Bachelor of Business Administration

San Juan, PR

Accounting (major) and Office Systems Administration (minor)

2015

University of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus

Certifications

Certified Tester, Foundation Level Acceptance Testing (CTFL-AcT)

Jan 2023 - No Exp. Date

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 23-CTFL-AcT-00000-USA

Certified Tester, Advanced Level Agile Technical Tester (CTAL-ATT)

Nov 2022 - No Exp. Date

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 22-CTAL-ATT-00026-USA

Certified Tester, Foundation Level Agile Tester (CTFL-AT)

Apr 2022 - No Exp. Date

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 22-CTFL-AT-00111-USA

Certified Tester, AT*SQA Testing Essentials

Dec 2021 - No Exp. Date

Association for Testing and Software Quality Assurance, Inc. (AT*SQA)

Credential ID: 21-AT*Essentials-00008-USA

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL)

Sep 2021 - No Exp. Date

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 21-CTFL-01698-USA